<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Kevin Kang Chen</title>
 <link href="http://kchens.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://kchens.github.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-10-05T22:00:11-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://kchens.github.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kevin Kang Chen</name>
   <email>kevin (dot) kang (dot) chen (a) gmail (dot) com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>switching to jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://kchens.github.com/2014/10/05/switched-to-jekyll.html"/>
   <updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://kchens.github.com/2014/10/05/switched-to-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;switching to jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;10 October 2014 - San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In creating my own blog, the most upsetting thing for me was that I had to start the css from scratch. Moreover, I wouldn&#39;t be able to save my content separate from the HTML file. Now, with Jekyll I can do that and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came across Jekyll four months ago, but opted to use the Ghost blogging platform because I would have online access to a markdown editor. It was a great choice at the time -- Ghost got me addicted to writing in markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In starting to blog for Dev Bootcamp, the thing I found most frustrating was that I had to specify dates, titles, and css multiple times over different HTML files (like specifying the date on the &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;post.html&lt;/code&gt;). What a massive waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll, I now have the benefits of ruby inside the HTML to save time. Currently, this markdown file &lt;code&gt;post.md&lt;/code&gt; has the following head:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
title: switching to jekyll
---

switching to jekyll
================

&amp;lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&amp;gt;10 October 2014 - San Francisco, CA&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if I want to the title to display across within the post and the homepage, I specify it in the &lt;code&gt;title: (POST TITLE HERE)&lt;/code&gt;. Then, it gets displayed in &lt;code&gt;switching to jekyll&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, given the way that the Jekyll files are set-up, the date is similarly displayed when entered here: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&amp;gt; (DATE HERE) &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one level of separation. We also have&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>age discrimination in tech</title>
   <link href="http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/31/tech-age-discrimination.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/31/tech-age-discrimination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;age discrimination in tech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;31 August 2014 - Burke, VA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a work in progress&lt;/em&gt;
Hair white at 50, my father dyed his hair for over a decade. Every few months, he&#39;d take the his little white rice bowl, pour the powder, mix the chemical into dark paste. He&#39;d prep his hair -- wet the ridges perfect like farming steppes -- slather the paste on, and let his hair set for double the time instructed. Something around an hour. An hour to have that black burn into his hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s the trade he made back in the late 90s. With four kids to support and poor English, he considered himself lucky. He found a great position at the #1 Aerospace Engineering Firm in the world -- with benefits! But, he had to transition from management to a front-line software engineer. With poor English and little desire to manage at a bigger firm, he believed he&#39;d be happy resigning himself to a position that demanded the most up-to-date skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he knew he was smart and hardworking. He postponed the start date of his position to learn a new programming language required for his job. In one month, he read that book back-to-back three times. With his hard work, he knew there were few reasons he&#39;d ever be fired. The only one that came to mind was that he might be too old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Life would have it, neither skills or hair dye could black out the ink on paper:  He was pushing, then pushed passed 65. Retirement age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Are you thinking about retirement?&quot; the manager asked. Of course, he had. Everyone has. My dad didn&#39;t respond, but 67 was the number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just a few months later, in August 2014, he was let go. Part of &quot;business conditions&quot;. Apparently, business conditions were so bad the company outbeat the S&amp;amp;P500 by 2x to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; That&#39;s the logic of business though. When you&#39;re judging someone by so-called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newrepublic.com/article/117088/silicons-valleys-brutal-ageism&quot;&gt;measureable&lt;/a&gt; standards of meritocracy and &lt;em&gt;unmeasureable&lt;/em&gt; standards of culture, it&#39;s easy to imply that you&#39;re contributing negatively to business conditions. Despite the fact that you may have trained fresh grads who would later become your managers, despite the fact that you have all this network knowledge that could help the firm become a wiser, smarter organization, it doesn&#39;t matter if you&#39;re not immediately useful. If you don&#39;t seem to put in as many hours as the next person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s just what is probably&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it&#39;s Silicon Valley or the greater engineering world at large, there are benefits to reap from old hands like my father. To quote &lt;em&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Ben Hammersley, a programmer and author who has advised the British government on creating a technology hub in London, points out that the incremental model largely explains Germany&#39;s economic strength. &quot;The majority of the German economy is light engineering. It&#39;s family-owned businesses engaged in long-term planning,&quot; he says. &quot;&#39;We&#39;re going to be around for another hundred years. What can we do to make a five percent improvement every year?&#39;&quot; By contrast, he says, economies that embrace the Silicon Valley model writ large--throwing massive amounts of money at highly speculative investments--are suspiciously bubble-prone.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s what Silicon Valley and the larger engineering and business world want: Disruption. Massive disruption that reaps massive profits. And they don&#39;t think that older engineers can deliver on that. Yet, while older engineers might not fit the typical mold of a &quot;innovative&quot; person, they have far more internal knowledge of how technical systems have worked in the past. And, not repeating mistakes for years or decades ago is important to moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of laying off and firing engineers after they are &quot;over-the-hill&quot;, I recommend putting in place transition program for engineers where &quot;wise&quot; ones can mentor workers of all ages and throughout all departments. In effect, these engineers would become advocates of the engineering culture across the whole business.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>abstract random thinking</title>
   <link href="http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/24/2014-thinking-style.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/24/2014-thinking-style</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;abstract random thinking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;24 August 2014 - Burke, VA&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;According to the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelearningweb.net/personalthink.html&quot;&gt;personal think&lt;/a&gt; quiz, my thinking style is &quot;abstract random&quot;. Besides being well-represented in the U.S. with 30% of the population having a similar style, what else does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, my people like (1) to experiment to find answers (2) work in a noncompetitive atmosphere, yet also likes competition (3) have personalized learning where personal attention and emotional support are given (4) activities that require them to use their intuition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes sense to me. In college, I was more of a liberal arts person -- engaged in one-on-one, late-night conversations regarding philosophy. I excelled at papers once I committed to them -- turning over the pages of every last footnote to make the &quot;perfect&quot; paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the inverse, all these supposed &quot;likes&quot; also make sense. While I was strong in math in high school, once the structure of the classroom of the room was removed, I flailed. And while, I wanted to work with people to further my understanding of a topic, I couldn&#39;t help but feel that I was behind others in those more technical topics. It wasn&#39;t very good for my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&#39;s no surprise that some things I -- an abstract random person -- struggle with are (1) routines (2) redoing anything once it&#39;s finished (3) working alone (4) expecting less emotional response from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Phase 0 so far, I have struggled with these routines, working alone on difficult problems, and shutting up during pairing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In pairing, I like to play-it-by-ear. As an abstract random person, I learn best by trial-and-error, so I have a hard time always explaining myself first -- then coding. Sometimes, I like to have the code speak for itself. When combined with my dislike of routine, I can come off as disrespectful towards a pair. In reality, it&#39;s me trying to figure out a problem. To solve the problem, I think I can be more upfront about my time limits as my drive to solve the problem is exacerbated by needing to get things done on time. To work better at this in the future, I will try to schedule my pairing sessions earlier in the week; secondly, I can let my pair know that I am working through trial-and-error so that I can better layout a concept. To me, making sure that we are both solid on the concepts is the most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding personal work, it&#39;s true that I rarely go back to my work to check it (after I&#39;ve double-checked and declared myself finished!) and I despise routine. To help guard against that, I&#39;ve begun to play around and taking more responsibility for my education. If need be, I&#39;ll read non-required portions of books/websites. I&#39;ll deep dive into StackOverflow to broaden my knowledge. That said, I like that parts of the curriculum, like the solo challenge, allow me to be as creative as I like. That there seems to be no hard grading criteria there. So, a second thing I will try to do more is to rush or try out the solo challenge first -- let myself experiment -- before finishing other parts of the curriculum for the week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>website design</title>
   <link href="http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/11/website-design-thoughts.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/11/website-design-thoughts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;website design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;11 August 2014 - Burke, VA&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Three of my favorite websites right now:
    1. Mint.com
    2. Slickdeals
    3. The Washington Post&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best user experience of any news site on the web right now has to be 3. The Washington Post. Whereas other news sites are concerned with users staying on the page -- by clicking on different articles -- WP doesn&#39;t do that. When reading an article, it only shows one sidebar of five other articles you might be interested in. No top banner of articles to distract you from the title or beginning of an article -- something which NYTimes and WSJ do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, I don&#39;t actually read the WP. I just went onto their website the other day and fell in love with all the white space the site designers provided. It&#39;s literally breathing room for my mind to think while reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few words, the WP is streamlined, simple, yet inviting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing WP to the other two sites I mentioned is no contest. Mint.com is cluttered with information as well as Slickdeals. However, while the user experience may not be the best in terms of simplicity, both applicaitons do their best given the type of work they do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a site that aggregates the hundreds, thousands, hundreds of thousands of dollars of a person&#39;s networth, Mint.com does a fantastic job as getting the user directly to the information they need -- be an old transaction from years ago or a new credit card offer they&#39;re eligble for. Given the vast amounts of personalized data, I can and do spend hours on the site. It&#39;s practical, informative, interactive, and less-hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have similar feelings for website #2 Slickdeals. The one thing I would add though is that the website does a great job on the visual dashboard for deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most days, I won&#39;t know what I&#39;m looking for. Moreover, there are tens of items that are on the front-page each day, so reading the text descriptions is completely useless. Slickdeals highlights which deals I should really pay attention to with pictures, a fire symbol for &quot;hot&quot; deals, and the number of &quot;thumbs up&quot; (recs) a deal has received. That way, I can always be sure that I am getting the best, if not a great, deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>chefs kitchen</title>
   <link href="http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/11/chefs-kitchen.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://kchens.github.com/2014/08/11/chefs-kitchen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;chefs kitchen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;08 August 2014 - Burke, VA&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m more excited to attend Dev Bootcamp after watching Shereef&#39;s fireside talk. I&#39;m ecstatic to be surrounded by people who are committed to programming for 12+ hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of this year, I began to self-teach myself programming. I locked myself up in my room for pretty much the whole day, for six days a week. However, it was so easy to procrastinate and get discouraged working by myself. With the Dev Bootcamp community, it&#39;s intensity, and it&#39;s emphasis on kindness (amongst other traits), I hope work beside those who will elevate me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My expectations changed after watching the video in regards that I might be &quot;too&quot; advanced. As I&#39;ve worked through the Hartl Tutorial several times now -- and have even built a few sites based on tutorials, I feel like I have a descent grasp on Rails. However, I do see the experience as one where I&#39;m internalizing coding and how to become better at the EQ side of programming. I haven&#39;t paired much before, so doing so will help me further these goals. In this regard, I&#39;ll always be a student; everyone will be my teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>